CURRICULUM VITAE

CARLOS STANLEY D'SA

Qatar.

Mobile- +974 3346 9974 Driving License **QATAR- Auto**

Skype: stanroadie

Email: stanroadie@hotmail.com

nley1@yahoo.co.in



OBJECTIVE

With 14+ years of my Engineering/Facilities management experience in the hospitality industry I'm seasoned to contribute in the most effective manner to the Mission, Vision, and Values of a company, to interact on a professional level with all stakeholders.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Company: IHG- Kimpton Al Rowda

Position: Duty Engineer

Duration: September 2022 till present

As a number 02 reporting to the DOE of engineering dept. Pre-opening of IHG upscale luxury brand KIMPTON my responsibilities are as below

- ➤ Inspection and testing of all MEP & HVAC systems of the property at all locations
- > Snagging and testing of all guest rooms and apartments
- > Attending all new equipment training and handover from contractor
- > Daily team members briefing and tasks assigning.
- > Supervision of external contractor AMC works.

Company:- MEP contracts freelancing. Duration:- May 2020 to August 2022

Currently involved in undertaking small MEP contracts for villas, offices and houses.

- > Electrical installations, wiring, repair and maintenance works.
- > Plumbing installations and maintenance.
- > AC units installations and maintenance.
- ➤ Metal cabinet fabrication works and shades installations.
- > Joinery works installations and maintenance.
- > Minor civil works.
- > Painting works.

Company: - Crowne Plaza Doha The Business Park,

Holiday Inn Doha The Business Park (IHG hotels)

Position: - Assistant Maintenance Manager-Cluster

Duration: - March 2017 to October 2019

As a number 03 in the engineering dept. and during Pre-opening of Holiday Inn my responsibilities are as below

Responsible for repair & maintenance of kitchen, laundry and plant rooms equipment with inhouse team of technicians or by external contractors.

New property testing and commissioning of all kinds of machineries and equipment, such as testing and snagging of all installations, equipment's BOH/FOH and guestrooms. snagging and following with contractors for Holiday Inn (pre-opening).

Daily staff briefing and follow up on tasks assigned to team members.

Follow up with external contractors for various quotations for additional projects going in the property to meet up deadlines.

Daily reporting to Assistant Chief & Chief Engineer of the various projects status.

Attending morning HODs meetings in absence of the Chief Engineer.

To know more about me and my experience kindly contact me on above mentioned contact details.

Company: - Meliá Hotels International, Dubai

Position: - Assistant Chief Engineer Duration June 2015 to April 2016

As a AHOD of engineering dept., my responsibilities were

Daily morning departmental briefing and job distribution, and follow ups on pending work list.

Monitoring workflow of all the engineering staff (Admin & field staff)

Overseeing functioning and operation engineering equipment in plant rooms

Checking and verifying daily log reports and energy consumption

Checking and verifying different quotes for material requirements and other jobs

Follow up of material requirements with different vendors, purchasing and finance dept.

Follow up of ongoing hotel new projects

Planning, scheduling and follow up on preventive maintenance programs.

Co-ordinating and following up with external contractors for timely completion on ongoing projects and maintenance services.

Planning, coordinating and following up on AMC for different maintenance services.

Supporting Chief Engineer for decision making related to departmental budgeting and job planning and execution.

Evaluating & comparing several quotations for effective cost saving.

Staff performance appraisal and counseling.

Attending HODs meeting during Chief engineer absence.

Company: - Jumeirah at Etihad Towers, Abu Dhabi

Position: - Team Leader (Duty Engineer) **Duration: -** April 2012 to April 2015

My responsibilities include (especially electrical section)

Taking care of the day to day engineering department operations and maintenance issues related to all trades.

Assists in managing the physical plant including equipment, refrigeration, HVAC, plumbing, water treatment, electrical and fire life safety systems.

Maintains and operates equipment at optimum effectiveness, efficiency and safety

Fully responsible repair, servicing and maintenance of Club Car buggies.

Planning and scheduling PPM of electrical equipment & guest rooms.

Daily staff briefing and follow up HOTSOS & PRIMA job/work order distribution trade wise.

Conducting monthly smoke detector tests, emergency lights tests, ELCB tests, PAT, generator and fire pump tests and records.

All swimming pools and water features electrical safety inspection and testing.

Preparing/conducting tutorials and training for colleague developments.

Co-ordinating follow up with contractors to rectify pre-opening MEP defects. etc.

External contractors monitoring and managing FLS test reports and follow up e.g. Kitchen ANSUL system servicing, LV room distribution and LV switchgear safety inspection, water sample collection and testing, kitchen hood and ecology unit servicing,

Coordinating with other departments for maintenance issues, mostly with housekeeping and FO for room PPM and out order room releases.

___Preparing day end and month end reports and reporting to Resident engineer and Director of Engineering.

<u>As a EHS representative at Jumeirah at Etihad Towers (Environmental Health and Safety committee)</u>

Identifying potential risks at the workplace and preparing risk assessment plans.

PPM of all engineering facilities and maintaining FLS (Fire Life Safety) guidelines and procedures. Maintaining all the records for future reference.

Follow up and managing GREEN GLOBE initiatives and suggestions to Director of Engineering

Conducting monthly training for Elevator trapped rescue (KONE elevators)

Follow up inspection comments from UAE government organizations'- ADTA, ADFCA and Abu Dhabi civil defense.

Participate and supervise mock up full building evacuation drills.

Monthly walkthrough in all plant rooms for identifying and eliminating potential risks of equipment and colleagues

Helps ensure regulatory compliance to facility regulations and safety standards

Ensures compliance with Jumeirah Engineering departmental policies, standards and procedures

Addressing colleagues' operational issues, guidance and counseling.

Certified first aider by National Ambulance UAE.

Passed basic KNX course by ABB, Dubai UAE Boom lift/ lift license holder 1b and 3b type.

Level 2 certificate holder in Health and Safety in workplace from Chartered Institute of Environmental Health-CIEH

Company: - Constance Halaveli Resort, Maldives

Position: - Team Leader (Electrical)

Duration: - September 2008 to April 2012

At Pre-Opening stage

During the Pre-Opening stage of the resort I was part of, for testing and commissioning of all kinds of machinery and equipment, such as testing and snagging of all installations, equipment and guest villas.

M&E snagging of all buildings, all beach and water villas.

Meggering of all power cables and wiring, test commissioning of guest villas

Assisting contractors to carry out load test of 1000 KVA gensets,11KV transformers etc.,

Testing and commissioning of Kitchen and laundry equipment.

Promoted as a Team Leader (Electrical)

Provide functional direction to team members for ongoing maintenance work. Participate and lead for decommissioning and commissioning of equipment for preventive maintenance

Planning and executing PMS programs of electrical equipment, guest villas and staff accommodation.

Planning and executing energy conservation programs.

Preparing daily and month end reports for jobs done and reporting to Chief Engineer

Attending guest villas and public area complaints.

Repair and maintenance of external lighting and fittings

R&M of Kitchen and laundry equipment.

R&M of fire alarm panel and fire input devices

R&M of electrical equipment and installations

Company:-Intercontinental The Grand Resort, Goa India (Now-The Lalit)

Position:-GTM Electrician (Plant operator), promoted as Senior GTM Electrician

Duration: - March 2004 to September 2008

Power Systems

33KV power supply-maintaining the voltage, recording the HV/LV readings etc.

33KV/415volts, 2200 KVA transformer-monitoring the input/output voltage, winding & oil temperatures, changing the voltage tapings whenever required & preventive maintenance etc.

2000 KVA central AVR-monitoring input/output voltage. Winding & oil temperatures etc.

Operating open overhead HV/LV isolators.

Operation and maintenance of HV/LV switchgears. Check and servicing of ACBs. Check and settings of protection relays governing HT/LT panels.

2x1000KVA and 1x500KVA DG sets CUMMINS/STAMFORD-switching on/off, monitoring oil, HSD &water levels and pressures, carrying out preventive maintenance, oil, fuel and air filters changing etc.

Operation & maintenance of 2x850kg/hr non-IBR steam boilers(make-THERMAX) periodically coil descaling, servicing of reciprocating piston type feed water pumps, plate type heat exchangers etc.

Operation of capacitor banks, setting and correction of power factor controllers. Troubleshooting and repair of star/delta starters, 1phase/3phase circuits, servicing of ACBs.

Regular inspection of all machineries, adjustments of a variety if valves and switches.

Battery voltage and specific gravity check.

Provide functional direction to juniors for ongoing maintenance work. Participate and lead for decommissioning and commissioning of equipment for preventive maintenance.

Recording and analyzing hourly and day end 24hrs reports of all machineries and parameters like HSD consumption, power consumption, water consumption log sheet preparing of breakdowns and repairs carried out. Associating with assistant engineers and reporting to the Chief Engineer.

HVAC Systems

3x250 tonne, R134a, screw type Chillers (make-Trane)-maintaining the entering and leaving chilled water and condenser water temperatures and other parameters.

VFDs and controllers-maintaining the system voltage and frequency at all times.

LT motors and pumps-servicing, Split case pumps servicing, bearing changing, mechanical seal changing whenever and wherever required.

Servicing and purging of FCUs(fan cooling units) and AHUs (air handling units)-motor belt tension testing and pulleys check etc.

Repairing and servicing of cooling tower fans.

Water Treatment Plants

Filtration, chemical dosing and pH testing of domestic water.

Periodically backwash and rinse of filtration vessels etc.

Hydropneumatic vessels pressure and air checks.

Servicing of air compressors etc.

Softener recharging, water softening and ppm testing.

Water chemical dosing and temperature monitoring.

Chemical dosing in cooling tower trays.

Maintaining and monitoring firefighting systems pressures.

Kitchen Equipment

Servicing and preventive maintenance of 3phase/1phase ovens.

Repair and maintenance of other equipment such as juicers, blenders, bone cutters, dough machine, slicer machine dish washers etc.

Repair and maintenance of masala grinders for bearing and belt checks.

Guest Rooms (255rooms and 10 villas)

Attending guest room maintenance complaints.

Planning and carrying out preventive maintenance of 255 guest rooms and 10 villas.

Arrange power requirements for outdoor parties and events.

From 20th January '03 to 30th June '03 (part time)

At Hello Information Services Pvt.Ltd Porvorim, a media company which runs two tourism publications namely Hello City and Hello Travel Talk, I worked as Marketing Executive for space selling and also increasing the client network.

Company: Goa Shipyard Ltd., Vasco-da-Gama, Position: - National Apprenticeship-Electrician

Duration: - April 2001 to April 2002

During the one year Apprenticeship course as a trainee I worked on warships for panel working and testing of sophisticated electrical machines like MSBs, high frequency convertors, motors, Transformers, auto changeover switches, Russian DG sets etc. I am also familiar with ship drawings and readings

QUALIFICATIONS

ACADEMIC

LEVEL	INSTITUTE	RESULT
S.S.C. X th	St.Anthony's High School Galgibaga.Canacona.Goa	PASS

PROFESSIONAL

COURSE/DIPLOMA	INSTITUTE	RESULT	DURATION	%
Electrician	N.C.V.T.Govt.I.T.I.Canacona.Goa	PASS	1998-2000	72
N.C.V.T.Apprenticeship in Electrician	Goa Shipyard Ltd. Apprenticeship training center Vasco-da-gama	PASS	2001-2002	69

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

COURSE	INSTITUTE	SUBJECTS	RESULT
Become a Project Manager	LinkedIn Learning	Project Management Skills	Preparation for PMP certification
Fundamentals of Residential Property Management	UDEMY	Leasing, Maintenance, Operations, Service Excellence	Completed
Basic KNX course	ABB Dubai LLC	Theoretical exam-KNX communication and Bus	PASS

		Devices. Practical exam-Basic KNX project	
Standard first Aid	National Ambulance-UAE	First Aid, CPR & AED	PASS
	Chartered Institute of Environmental Health	Safety and hygiene at workplace	PASS
Basic Fire Fighting and Fire Safety	ALARMS-Maldives	Theory and practical in fire fighting	PASS
Computer Awareness Course	N.S.I.T. Margao. Goa	MS. Word, MS. Excel, MS. PowerPoint, Internet & Email.	PASS

OTHER KNOWLEDGE

: Proficient in FBM

Proficient in QEMS
Proficient in OPERA

Proficient in SIEMENS Prisma

Proficient in HOTSOS

Proficient in MS Outlook Express.

Proficient in Espresso Command center

HOBBIES

: Music and Movies, Net Surfing,

Playing TT, Photography/Videography, Nature etc.

PERSONAL DETAILS

DATE OF BIRTH : 2nd February 1980

ADDRESS (permanent) : H. No-266, Bategal, Sadolxem,

Canacona.Goa-403 702

MARITAL STATUS : Married

PASSPORT DETAILS: Passport No. V3034107

Date of Issue-15-11-2021 Place of Issue-PANAJI Date of Expiry-14-11-2031